Timothy Peterson

Beaverton, Or 97133 (619) 251-2984

<u>Timothy.m.peterson.jr@gmail.com</u> <u>Github.com/fridayfred3p</u> <u>Linkedin.com/in/timothypetersonjr2/</u>

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

A proven leader with six years of military experience as a nuclear electronics technician supervisor and five years of experience as a planarization manufacturing technician, operating in a variety of challenging fast paced environments. An expert full stack web developer with 6 months of experience. Familiar with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Firebase, Ionic Mobile Framework, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express & Handlebar Js. Possess exceptional experience with troubleshooting, repairing, and conducting operational testing of nuclear reactor plant instrumentation and control equipment. Expertly partners with engineering and manufacturing to coordinate effective use of resources, ensuring maximum wafer outs while maintain minimum tool downtime. Detail-oriented, works well under pressure, and possesses outstanding analytical and communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Software Development
- Peer Trainer
- Technical Operator
- Electrical Safety
- Role Model
- Maintenance Scheduling
- Computer Science Fundamentals
- Communication Skills
- Comparative Analyses

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2020 to Present Full Stack Web Developer

Computer Skills:

- ➤ Cofounder the Easy Job Search portal which allows user to search for thousands of open job positions.
- > Created a website which displays weather conditions at a user's location or wherever city they'd like to search.
- > Crafted an expert daily task scheduler allowing users to properly plan out each hour of the day for max efficiency.

2013 to Present Senior Manufacturing Technician, Intel

Operations:

- Qualified BE/FE Planar AC, expertly processes multiple layers of WIP on planarization toolset.
- Qualified L1 Equipment Technician, performs various tool maintenance and assist senior personnel with critical equipment repairs.
- Qualified ERT Member, provides additional safety and casualty response to tool and personnel issues.

Analysis:

> Collects and evaluates operating data to conduct online equipment adjustment and ensure process optimization.

- > Responsible for improvement of processes, troubleshooting nonstandard events in the production line, and reviewing technological health and stability
- Executes prompt escalation, documentation, and disposition of lots on hold and effectively performs recipe changes, updates and uploads as directed by module engineers

Training:

- ➤ Knowledgeable on Intel training systems (Infinity, 1Stop2) and provides advance peer training
- > Escalates resources needed to module engineers and management appropriately to drive team to obtain 100% training matrix completion goal
- > Develops training packages, writes BKM's and other training materials for module implementation

2006 to 2012 Nuclear Electronics Technician, US Navy

Leadership:

- Senior maintenance team supervisor, expertly managed and supervised 20 technicians in the Reactor Controls Division.
- ➤ Implemented and coordinated daily meetings to disseminate workload requirements ensuring preventative maintenance occurred as scheduled, actions resulted in zero reactor incidents.
- > Trained junior personnel in the proper procedures to conduct preventative maintenance, monitor reactor controls, and emergency shutdown procedures of the nuclear power plant.
- ➤ Routinely mentored junior personnel through suggesting appropriate training courses and conducting on hands training for trouble shooting techniques. This mentorship resulted in a highly trained workforce that practiced effective trouble shooting procedures to resolve numerous complex glitches thus preventing critical incidents.

Qualifications

- Qualified Reactor Technician, senior maintenance supervisor. Conducted complex maintenance evolutions on a critical reactor plant and recovering plant from various casualties affecting reactor instrumentation and control equipment.
- ➤ Qualified Reactor Operator, senior operating electronics technician watch-station. Duties involved control, critical power operations, maintenance, repair, and casualty control of the reactor plant.
- Qualified Shutdown Reactor Operator, senior watch-station in a shutdown reactor plant. Duties involved tight control over complex shutdown reactor plant maintenance, overall control of mechanical and electrical systems, as well as the responsibility for ship-wide electrical distribution.

Education

University of Oregon, Full Stack Web Developer BootCamp Course, Portland, Or	2020
Nuclear Reactor Prototype, Nuclear Power Training Unit, Saratoga Springs, NY	2007
Electronics Technician 'A' School, Naval Nuclear Power Training Command, Goose Creek, SC	2006
Nuclear Power School, Naval Nuclear Power Training Command, Goose Creek, SC	2006
Monte Vista High School, San Diego, Ca	2004